<resources>
    <string name="app_name">DS Wiki</string>
    <string name="world">World</string>
    <string name="characters">Characters</string>
    <string name="tools">Game tools</string>
    <string name="quotes">Quotes</string>
    <string name="episodes">Episodes</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="about_sam">Samuel "Sam" Porter Bridges is a legendary porter and member of Bridges who plays an integral role in expanding the Chiral Network and making the United Cities of America whole by embarking on a westward expedition.</string>
    <string name="about_fragile">Fragile\'s father was the founder of Fragile Express, and when he died, the torch was passed down to her. She and her company eventually merged with Higgs Monaghan\'s delivery company, drawn to his vision of the future.\n\n
Early on, they were highly successful in delivering supplies to those in the most remote of areas, but all too quickly it was discovered that Higgs was a terrorist leading the Homo Demens. They had gone from delivering food and medicine for communities to smuggling guns and bombs for terrorist cells. Fragile was tricked into bringing a nuclear bomb into Middle Knot City, resulting in the deaths of everyone there. Fragile discovered that Higgs was delivering another nuke to South Knot City and managed to steal it away from them, only to be caught by the terrorists. Fragile was stripped down to her underwear and given a choice by Higgs: save the city by running through timefall (which he had summoned) and throwing the bomb into a tar pit, or warping out of the area and saving herself, at the cost of all those who lived there. Fragile chose to save those in the city, and Higgs gave her a hood so that her face would be protected, wanting for her face to be a testament to those who crossed him (and for it to be remembered as belonging to the person who nuked Middle Knot City). Because of this, the rest of Fragile\'s body deteriorated as the price for South Knot\'s continued survival.\n\n
Fragile meets Sam while hiding in a cave to avoid the timefall, helping him evade BTs by telling him to hold his breath when around them. After the BTs leave, she and Sam shed tears as they watch the Extinction entities survey from the sky momentarily before vanishing. She offers Sam a job working for her, noting how difficult it is for a lone deliveryman to operate in the world, but Sam declines, preferring his solitude. Afterward, she warns Sam to be mindful of the BTs\' return and remarks that timefall cannot wash everything away – the ever-clinging past in particular – before departing.
</string>
    <string name="background">Background</string>
    <string name="background_sam1">Sam was born on November 9, to Clifford Unger and Lisa Bridges. In an effort to save his unborn son after Lisa was rendered brain dead in an accident, Cliff willingly placed Sam under the care of Bridges scientists conducting bridge baby experiments, but did so unaware of their true intentions: to use Sam as a sacrificial foundation for a new communications network as the first proper bridge baby. Upon learning of such from an old comrade and friend, Cliff attempted to abduct Sam from a Bridges facility, but was gunned down in the process, resulting in his and Sam\'s deaths. On the Beach, Sam was healed and brought back to life by Amelie, who bestowed to him the ability of repatriation. No longer viable as a bridge baby by virtue of being a repatriate, he was taken into Bridget\'s care and raised as her son, Sam Strand. However, his revival upset the balance of life and death, triggering the Death Stranding.\n\n In his youth, as a sufferer of DOOMS, Sam had severe nightmares and would find himself stranded on the Beach unable to find his way out. Always there for him in such moments, Amelie would arrive to calm Sam and help him make his way out of the Beach. Sam fashioned a quipu for Amelie in the world of the living, and was able to bring it with him to the Beach, where he gifted it to Amelie as a representation of their bond. \n\n At some point, Sam joined Bridges, and due to his DOOMS and ability of repatriation would become an essential member of the core team as the organization\'s mandate expanded. He met a psychotherapist named Lucy, who tried to help him overcome his aphenphosmphobia. The two fell in love, married, and eventually conceived a child, a daughter whom they intended to name Louise. After being subjected to the nightmares of DOOMS sufferers as the bearer of Sam\'s child, Lucy committed suicide which took their unborn daughter with her. Her death caused a voidout in the satellite town of UCA–01–0C, leaving Sam, a repatriate, as the sole survivor in the area and the primary suspect of the incident. Due to public pressure and guilt, he left Bridges and became a freelance porter, isolating himself from society and cutting himself off from the living. His former co-workers suspected that his resignation was Sam\'s own way of taking responsibility for the incident.</string>
    <string name="background_fragile">Fragile is controlled and intelligent, as shown when she tells Sam to be quiet while under threat from BTs, clearly knowing how to effectively deal with them in a calm fashion. She also remains at ease when she is captured by the Homo Demens, despite being held at gunpoint.\n\n
She appears to have a fond taste for cryptobiotes, even commenting to Sam, that much like a proverbial apple; "A cryptobiote a day, keeps the timefall away." Due to Fragile\'s past circumstances and her ability as a "jumper," she must maintain a steady diet of cryptobiotes to stabilize her aged body. Despite all the suffering she has experienced she maintains a friendly and positive personality, thus demonstrating great strength.\n\n

Fragile is a white young woman in her late 20s or early 30s with blonde hair and blue eyes. Most of her body is aged due to the timefall with which Higgs tortured her. This has probably lowered her life expectancy and health.
\n\n
She uses a black jacket that looks like leather and has the name of her company in the sleeves and a big logo in the back. Also has a blue line detail in the front with the company name. This jacket has the function of detecting high chiralium concentrations. When this happens spikes pop outs on the shoulders. Her hands are always covered with black gloves.
\n\n
Her pants are also black with a blue line on the sides and her boots are black too. These clothes also have the appearance of being made of leather. Besides all this Fragile always carries an "umbrella" which is actually a navigation device to guide her travels through the beaches.\n\n
Fragile possesses DOOMS with an extinction factor that is higher than Sam\'s, allowing her to see BTs. Fragile\'s DOOMS allows her to teleport to other locations in the world by moving through her Beach and reappearing in the material world. Doing so causes fatigue, so she uses this ability cautiously. She later helps Sam travel to Edge Knot City by sending him through her Beach to locations with high Chiralium density connected to the Chiral Network.
</string>
    <string name="name">Name:</string>
    <string name="gender">Gender:</string>
    <string name="gender_male">male</string>
    <string name="gender_female">female</string>
    <string name="hair_color">Hair color:</string>
    <string name="eye_color">Eye color:</string>
    <string name="cast">Cast:</string>
    <string name="status">Status:</string>
    <string name="status_alive">alive</string>
    <string name="status_dead">deceased</string>
    <string name="status_unknown">unknown</string>
    <string name="name_sam">Sam</string>

    <string name="color_blue">blue</string>
    <string name="color_brown">brown</string>
    <string name="color_blonde">blonde</string>
    <string name="color_gray">gray</string>


    <string name="cast_norman">Norman Reedus</string>
    <string name="cast_fragile">Léa Seydoux</string>
    <string name="cast_deadman">"Guillermo del Toro "</string>
    <string name="cast_mama">Margaret Qualley</string>
    <string name="background_deadman">It is known that 70% of his body was harvested from cadavers, while the remaining 30% was grown from pluripotent stem cells. He was originally a coroner at some point.\n\nAfter the Death stranding, a final interview with Deadman reveals the truth about his origin. His story of being created from pluripotent stem cells was a fake (more of an exaggerated truth): he was born via in-vitro fertilization but in an artificial womb. However, he did acquire lacking organs from cadavers. He also reveals that during his time with Lou, he was able to visit a Beach, though not his own. Despite not having his own Beach, he is able to traverse the Beaches through connections from others, and has thus "put a great many worries of mine [Deadman] in perspective."\n\nDeadman is affable and well-meaning. However, he is ashamed of his nature as an artificial human, calling himself "Frankenstein's monster". This has instilled a great deal of loneliness in him, and he reaches out to Sam as a result.</string>
    <string name="name_fragile">Fragile</string>
    <string name="name_deadman">Deadman</string>
    <string name="about_deadman">Deadman is a main character in Death Stranding. He appears to be involved in the medical field for Bridges. He is an artificial human, created from a combination of cadavers and stem cells.</string>
    <string name="about_mama">Mama, real name Målingen, is a main character in Death Stranding. She is affiliated with Bridges and is the twin sister of Lockne. She is one of the greatest scientists in the UCA; inventing a plethora of gadgets and tools for porters to use. Additionally, She is one of the creators of the Chiral Network.</string>
    <string name="background_mama">Mama and Lockne were genius twin sisters born with DOOMS, which gave them the ability to communicate with each other across the world. Together, they each made half of the Chiral Network: Mama, the hardware, and Lockne, the software. Their equal genius and close bond was so great that many believed them to be the "same person in two bodies."\n\nHowever, Mama\'s ovaries were unable to produce eggs and Lockne\'s uterus was incapable of carrying a child to term. While both were initially accepting of these circumstances, Lockne eventually fell in love with a Bridges member and wanted to develop a relationship with him. However, he died in an accident, leaving Lockne depressed and suicidal. Mama could feel this, and wanting to help her, proposed to Lockne that they should "have a baby." Using the deceased\'s sperm, Lockne\'s eggs, and Mama\'s uterus, the two sisters were able to create Lockne a child that would be carried to term by Mama.</string>
    <string name="name_mama">Mama</string>
    <string name="cast_higgs">Troy Baker</string>
    <string name="about_higgs">Higgs Monaghan, also known as the \"Man in the Golden Mask\", was a porter and a close associate of Fragile Express, until he met and was seduced by Amelie. Higgs acted as the figurehead of the militant separatist group known as the Homo Demens to maintain the independence of Edge Knot City on Amelie\'s behest.</string>
    <string name="name_higgs">Higgs</string>
    <string name="background_higgs">Higgs was raised by his uncle early in his life after both of his parents died. He grew up thinking the shelter was the entire world, and his uncle would beat him whenever he asked about the outside world or tried to leave the shelter. Higgs would eventually kill his uncle in self-defense with a knife and witness the body going necro. Higgs took the corpse out and felt the Beached Things slowly approaching, unknowingly gaining his DOOMS in the process. In time, he would find out that his powers were triggered by death.\n\nHiggs became a porter, being the only job he could do to survive. One time, he delivered medicine to a prepper living close to him only to find that he had died. It was too late to take the body to an incinerator. Instead, he took it to BT territory, where he started feeling the BTs reacting to the corpse and began having visions of the Beach, leaving Higgs to wonder if he had DOOMS.\n\nWith time, Higgs came to enjoy helping people, being an essential part of a community, defying his dad\'s teachings about caring only about oneself. However, when he was unable to help one of his porter partners that was calling for help lost in the mountains, Higgs began to question his powers to detect BTs, feeling them dwindle. Also at this time, Higgs began reading a book called Wisdom of the Egyptians, about how the ancient Egyptians\' concepts of life and death seemed to predict the changes brought on by the Death Stranding. Borrowing from the old pharaohs\' wisdom, he began to wear a golden death mask, "but one for living—for ruling".</string>
    <string name="color_black">black</string>
    <string name="cast_diehardman">Tommie Earl Jenkins</string>
    <string name="about_diehardman">Die-Hardman, born John Blake McClane, is the third and current President of the United Cities of America and Director of Bridges.</string>
    <string name="name_diehardman">Diehardman</string>
    <string name="background_diehardman">In his early adulthood, John Blake McClane was a member of the US Special Forces, serving under the command of Captain Clifford "Cliff" Unger. During his time in the military, John earned the nickname "Die-Hardman" due to surviving against impossible odds (although John believed it was due to Unger\'s leadership rather than his own ability). John later left the Army and began working for Bridges, eventually becoming special advisor and security guard for President Bridget Strand. During this time, he became part of the Bridge Baby experiments. Among the BBs was the unborn son of Unger, who had submitted the child following an accident that left Unger\'s then-pregnant wife brain-dead. </string>
    <string name="cast_amelie">Lindsay Wagner</string>
    <string name="about_amelie">"Samantha America Strand, widely known as \"Amelie\", is the \"ka\" (soul) of the sixth extinction entity, publicly recognized as the daughter of her counterpart \"ha\" (body), President Bridget Strand.  "</string>
    <string name="name_amelie">Amelie</string>
    <string name="background_amelie">In the story fabricated by Bridget, her daughter, Samantha America "Amelie" Strand, was born with "locked-in syndrome", a condition that caused her soul to be born on the Beach. This separation of body and soul caused her to be hospitalized for her entire childhood. However, her DOOMs abilities were unprecedented, and by the age of twenty, she developed the ability to transport herself to and from the Beach, where she ended up spending the majority of her time. Due to her condition, Bridget kept Amelie\'s existence secret, but Amelie chose to move with her mother upon her recovery.\n\nBridget Strand, the sixth extinction entity, developed uterine cancer in her early twenties. During surgery, her ka and ha separated, with her ka remaining on the Beach. Strangely, both halves of her essence were aware of each other\'s existence and worked in tandem.\n\nDue to the timeless nature of the Beach, Bridget\'s ka did not age, and the age gap between her and the ha became noticeable. Eventually, rumors began to spread of a younger version of Bridget wandering the White House. In order to deflect suspicion, Bridget created the persona of "Amelie" for her ka. The name "Amelie" itself was a portmanteau of "âme" (the French word for soul) and "lie", an admission of sorts that Amelie was "a soul that's a lie".</string>
    <string name="cast_cliff">Mads Mikkelsen</string>
    <string name="about_cliff">Clifford \"Cliff\" Unger was a United States Army Special Forces captain who was shot dead attempting to reclaim custody of his son from Bridges. Following his death, he became beached in a restless search for his \"BB\" as the \"Combat Veteran\".</string>
    <string name="background_cliff">Captain Clifford Unger served in the United States Army Special Forces before the Death Stranding, having fought in Iraq, Afghanistan, and many other countries. He was known for consistently bringing back his unit alive and unscathed. Among his unit was a soldier known as John Blake McClane, who would later go by the name "Die-Hardman", a moniker given to him because Cliff kept saving him and bringing him home. Eventually, Cliff fell in love with and married Lisa Bridges, and they conceived a son. Because of his impending fatherhood, Cliff left active duty to be with his family.\n\nFollowing his return, Cliff and Lisa were involved in an accident, from which both came out alive, but with Lisa rendered brain dead and their unborn son at risk of death. Desperate to save his family, Cliff willingly brought them to Bridges for experimental procedures, not realizing what would become of his son. Lisa was put on life support to prevent her death and necrosis, and their baby inside a portable pod full of amniotic fluid, keeping him suspended in development until further notice.\n\nFollowing his return, Cliff and Lisa were involved in an accident, from which both came out alive, but with Lisa rendered brain dead and their unborn son at risk of death. Desperate to save his family, Cliff willingly brought them to Bridges for experimental procedures, not realizing what would become of his son. Lisa was put on life support to prevent her death and necrosis, and their baby inside a portable pod full of amniotic fluid, keeping him suspended in development until further notice.</string>
    <string name="name_cliff">Cliff</string>
    <string name="color_hazel">hazel</string>
    <string name="about_lockne">Lockne is a gifted technician who serves as the overseer of Mountain Knot City. She is the twin sister of Mama and one of the creators of the chiral network.</string>
    <string name="background_lockne">Mama and Lockne were identical twin sisters born with DOOMS that granted them the ability to communicate with each other irrespective of their locations. Gifted with great intellect, they soon found themselves as accomplished technicians, each responsible for creating half of the Chiral Network. Mama created the hardware, and Lockne wrote its software. Their equal genius and close bond was so great that many believed they were the "same person in two bodies".Though the sisters share a great many traits, their few differences tend to stand in complete opposition to one another. For one, Målingen has never wanted kids, while Lockne loved them, but was infertile. At some point, Lockne was in a relationship with someone from Bridges I. Unfortunately, it ended tragically in accident. His sudden departure left her greatly depressed. However, he did have sperm frozen possibly in preparation of the unforeseen. Sensing her sister\'s distress, Målingen offered to be the surrogate mother of her child. Strangely, around the child\'s due date, Målingen suddenly cut off all communications with her and disappeared. Lockne was furious as she thought that Målingen had ran off with her child.</string>
    <string name="name_lockne">Lockne</string>
    <string name="name_hearthman">Hearthman</string>
    <string name="cast_hearthman">Nicolas Winding Refn</string>
    <string name="about_hearthman">"Heartman is a Bridges member who researches the Death Stranding.  "</string>
    <string name="background_hearthman">Heartman began his studies of the Beach after losing his family in a unique manner; while he was at a hospital undergoing heart surgery, his wife and daughter returned home to retrieve something for him - only to find themselves caught in two simultaneous voidouts which left a heart-shaped crater. The hospital was not directly affected, but the shock wave caused the power to fail, and with it Heartman\'s life support. Heartman found himself on the Beach, surrounded by the souls of the newly deceased, including his family. However, the ICU\'s emergency generator activated, allowing the defibrillator to re-start his heart and forcibly return him to the living world.</string>
    <string name="episode">Episode:</string>
</resources>